#### RADHAKRISHNAN. K.G

SCM - Logistics Professional with 20+ years Exposure to Multiple product - MNCs

Mobile: +91-9840279776,

yahoo.com,

#### gradha123 @ gmail.com

## **Experience Summary:**

- 25 + years of Functional Expertise in Supply Chain Management.
- 3 + years of Experience as SAP MM Core Team Member.

#### **SAP Skills:**

SAP MM Module ■ ECC 5.0 Version.

#### **Professional Experience:**

Present Position: Heading the Transport Division of M/s Suguna Foods Ltd, Coimbatore a 6000 Crore concern as AGM-Logistics, a Food Major having its wings spread across the entire INDIAN SUBCONTINENT & Neighboring countries Like Bangladesh, Sri Lanka etc., with a Fleet size of 350 Plus with Multiple usage from 16.12. 2016. This concern hold No: 3 Position in POULTRY industry in ASIA.

#### Core functions:

- Spearhead responsibility for managing the gamut of operations pertaining to Transport & Logistics operations.
- Planning and developing logistics network for ensuring seamless, cost-effective movement of Bulk material from Suppliers to ensure timely delivery to internal customers.
- Planning and developing suitable fleet vendors and negotiating with Vendors based on various criteria such as prices, quality improvement rate, timely delivery, credit terms, workshop, vehicle maintenance etc.
- Strengthening existing vendor source & developing alternate/back up suppliers.
- Preparation of Logistics Tender documents and finalisation of Logistics Contract and Implementation and monitoring the all the stages and review the shipment performance at the end of each shipments.
- Prepare efficient internal control systems to keep track of Strategic Supply Chain performance metrics
- Monitoring and adjusting the parameters logistics, lead time, production cycles, cycles of appeal etc
- Resolve customer complaints within minimum turnaround time by identifying and removing areas
  of obstructions.
- Develop and track customer satisfaction metrics to evaluate and improvise upon the current Supply Chain
- Responsible for Insurance-Contract Negotiation & finalisation, Coordination of Third Party Survey Reports, Legal disputes, Claims
- Interacting with regulatory authorities like Excise & Customs Departments for obtaining necessary licenses/sanctions and ensuring compliance with various statutory obligations.
- Safety Training for Truck crew about personnel, material and Road Safety.
- Negotiation and finalization of transport contract and responsible for dispatching the finished product through approved transporters.
- Identify the leverage opportunities across the supply chain to improve efficiencies and reduce costs: Coordinate with Custom House Agents, C&F Agents and other external agencies for ensuring timely clearances and cost-effective transport solutions.
- To improve fuel efficiency of all vehicles.
- Ensure all vehicles relate to GPRS and diesel theft control devices.
- Involve in transport vehicle purchase.
- Conduct a study on transport driver s compensation & benefits across all regions.
- Ensure all drivers Insurance and license renewal is taken care.
- Bring in new system of categorizing drivers into on-roll drivers and contract driver, need to

- eliminate off-roll drivers.
- Develop incentives schemes for drivers to improve efficiency.
- Approve POs for vehicle purchase and sales of old vehicle.

#### **PREVIOUS POSITION:**

Sr. Manager-Logistics and Head of Logistics function in M/s Butterfly Gandhimathi Appliances Itd, Chennai a leading Player in Home appliances industry from 23.05.2014 to 14.12.2016 handling the PAN India Operations from Chennai.

# Reporting to: Managing Director

# Job Responsibilities:

- Handling ALL India Logistics operations.
- Optimization of Transportation cost /Material safety by choosing the right Mode.
- > Consistently Monitor the Quality and efficiency of goods storage and Transportation.
- Finished good inventory Management, inventory Management & ageing analysis.
- Insurance management.
- Defective goods management.
- Demand forecasting & analysis.
- Monitoring Fleet of vehicles & transporters ensuring on time delivery & transit norms, analyzing the loss in transit and undertaking measures to control fleet Management.

Achievements: (1) Budgeted cost control (2) Saved a Huge freight amount thro Value Engineering (3) Vendors Development.

Manager- Logistics Heading the Logistics Function in M/s Godrej & Boyce Mfg co Ltd, Storage Solution group division from 21.11.2008 to 21.05.2014, a division offering Shop Floor Solutions & Space Management solution with their Vide range of Industrial Racking applications. Our division is representing the Leading Multinational Brand FAMI in INDIAN Sub-continent.

#### Reporting to: Asst Vice President (Operations)

## Job Responsibilities:

- Finalize, manage and co-ordinate with Transporters for Domestic & Export Operations.
- Ensure proper sequence and accurate dispatches as per Project requirement, DIRECT TO THE CUSTOMER
  SITE including ODC- Odd Size Cargo.
- Control Logistics cost through regular reviews.
- Close Co-ordination with FG, Field sale & projects for adherence to project schedule
- Managing the team and system to achieve a business volume of Rs. 30 Crores a month.
- Ensure proper documentation
- Statutory Compliance
- Comply with all Exports documentation and Bank Payment formalities
- Safety & Housekeeping.
- Cluster Management act ivies.
- ❖ OHSAS 18001 ACTIVIES.

Achievements: (1) Cost control as per the Budget Norms.

#### **PREVIOUS POSITION:**

Worked as a Production Planning Officer for Britannia Industries Ltd., Chennai. Britannia Industries Ltd., 850 crore FMCG Company with 80 SKU, 26 Brands and 450000 Tones P.A from 21.1.2004 to 20.11.2008

## Job Responsibilities: Related to SAP Activities:

- > Core team member for implementing SAP when new/ Change of production centers & Depots.
- ➤ Coordinating across 16 Production units & 15 Depots & Other dept s for solving sap related issues.
- For Uploading of individual Materials & BOMs for Each SKU after development stage to Production release.
- > Team Member of Replenishment system for smooth dispatches of every sku sonly thro SAP.
- New process / reports implementation in SAP.
- Gap analysis with regard to business process for continuous improvement & Finding solutions to bridge gaps.

# Job Responsibilities: Functional

## **Planning Material Procurement**

- Coordination with Purchase on material requirement
- Placement of Indent for material procurement based on stock levels & Rolling Forecast.
- Monitoring & Replenishment stock positions of all materials daily across 16 Production centers in the southern Region.
- Implementation of Replenishment for major ingredients
- ► Ensuring Smooth flow of Materials for Trouble Free Production across all the CP =s.

# Planning Production based on Sales requirement:

- > Implementation of stock norms for finished products at the Depots
- ➤ Planning production for the month s based on Sales Plan and to cover stock norms
- Stock norms based on products selling pattern
- > Daily review of CRSE % and Stock outs through SAP.
- Daily monitoring of both inventory and finished goods and effect changes in production.

## **Handling C&F Agents across Southern Region**

- > Study on Space utilization at CFA
- ➤ Number of C&FA 15 Nos
- Authority to handle operation Negotiation of rates with C&FA
- ➤ Identification of Slow moving / Two months Old SKU as

# **Transportation & Distribution:**

- Controlling Inbound and Outbound Logistics
- Continues follow up on in bound and outbound logistics to maintain stock norms
- Ensuring Truck Placement for Both Primary & Secondary Movement for smooth Despatches.

#### Replenishment System Implemented at Production / Storage Location

- > Team member of Replenishment System
- ➤ Norms for all SKU = s at Storage location
- Ensuring 95 % CRSE across the Region.
- Ensuring Stock out Less than 5% across all the depots.
- Effective management of Depot Space.

## **Previous Work Experience:**

M/s SembCorp Logistics India P Ltd, Chennai. Name of the Firm Services/ Products Warehousing & Logistics Depot in Charge. Designation Client M/s Godrej & Boyce Mfg ltd. 11.11.2002 to 20.01.2004. Period Functional Area Warehousing & Logistics of Appliance Division of Client. Achievements Freight Reduction of Primary Freight for the Client. Name of the Firm M/s Steelage Industries Ltd Chennai. Services/ Products Fire Vehicles & Extinguishers. Asst Manager (Materials) Designation Period 18.05.2001 to 31.08.2002 > Functional Area Material Planning, Purchase, Stores, ISO 9001 Activities. Achievements 1. Cost Reduction by Value Engg & Alternate Source Devp. 2. Successful implementation of ERP systems in Materials Name of the Firm M/s KONE Elevator India ltd, Chennai. Services/ Products Elevator & Escalators Designation Sr. Engineer(Purchase) 06.08.1998 to 09.05.2001 Period Functional Area Procurement Head of Electrical & Electronics Component Team for the Industry. Achievements Cost Reduction by New Vendor Development. Effective implementation of TWO BIN system for Trouble free production Effective implementation of ISO 9001. Indigenization of Imported Components. M/s Sea Horse Industries Ltd. Trichy. Name of the Firm : Electrical Energy Meters & Electro Mechanical indiginised Services/ Products Russian systems for Defense application (Projects Division) Designation Purchase Officer. Period 01.12.1993 to 29.07.1998. Functional Area Procurement of Materials for Defense Projects. Achievements NEW vendor development for Critical compoents to support Indigenization activities of the Projects division. Cost Reduction. Co-coordinator for successful Implementation of Coincap ERP-Package in the Defense Purchase area during my Tenure. Name of the Firm M/s Electro Tronics, Trichy. Services/ Products Distributor of Various TMI Products. Designation Sales Executive. Period 01.07.1992 to 30.11.1993 > Functional Area Marketing & New customer development. Achievements 1. Introduction of NEW clients for Business Development.

# **Education Qualification:**

- **B.E** (Electronics & Communication) from **University of Madras** with First Class (Year: 1991)
- Post Graduate Diploma in Materials Management from Annamalai University, (Year: 2000)

## **Personal Profile:**

Name : K.G. RADHA KRISHNAN

Date of Birth & Age : 05.12.1969, 47 years

Email Address : grk 123@ yahoo.com, gradha123@gmail.com

Address for Communication : Flat NO: F-1, First Floor, ## G" - Block,

Sunshine ENCLAVE,

Jyothiba Avenue, Melamaiyur,

Chengelpattu 603 002

Ph no: 98402 -79776, 8870908952, 90439 12306

Permanent Address : K.G. RADHA KRISHNAN,

17, Thennai Marathu Street, Udamalpet, Coimbatore District

Pin • 642 126